<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Eirik&#39;s Tech Blog</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Eirik&#39;s Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>habbis@medmail.ch (Eirik Habbestad Helleve)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>habbis@medmail.ch (Eirik Habbestad Helleve)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 17:21:49 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup Linux Virtualization with KVM</title>
      <link>/post/setup_kvm_virt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 17:21:49 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>habbis@medmail.ch (Eirik Habbestad Helleve)</author>
      <guid>/post/setup_kvm_virt/</guid>
      <description>Linux Virtualization with KVM You are free to use this I use this blog like a wiki to write things I learn.
Here are some other Open Source Virtualization projects.
 KVM - Kernel-based Virtual Machine
 Xen
 VirtualBox
 UML - User Mode Linux
 LXD/LXC
 Docker
  What is KVM?
KVM is a hypervisor built into the Linux Kernel and it
allows Linux desktop or server to simulate multiple piece of hardware.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup a server with zfs and docker</title>
      <link>/post/zfs_server/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 10:34:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>habbis@medmail.ch (Eirik Habbestad Helleve)</author>
      <guid>/post/zfs_server/</guid>
      <description>Setup a server with zfs and docker You are free to use this as you wish I am also using this as my own wiki to remember how to do stuff. I hope this can help other people.
I am going to set up a Digitalocean vps with docker and testing out zfs as docker storage driver.
I am going to use Ubuntu 16.04 since it have a native zfs binary.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lxd</title>
      <link>/post/lxd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 21:03:41 +0200</pubDate>
      <author>habbis@medmail.ch (Eirik Habbestad Helleve)</author>
      <guid>/post/lxd/</guid>
      <description>LXD setup I am now trying out LXC and LXD both are cool technologies. Lxd it is a·
hyper-visor for lxc containers(linux containers).
So why LXD/LXC? It has benefits like being closer to the metal. And it behaves more like a
virtual machine and it it can be easier to understand the concept behind it.
Lxd is also more like Freebsd jails and the solaris zones.
And lxd/lxc consisting of namspaces to isolate process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>